EVA GARCIA MARTIN

Data Scientist

Data Scientist with several years of academic and industrial experience researching and developing machine learning algorithms and out-of-the-box solutions for real world applications. Expertise in public speaking and communicating ideas to diverse teams and audiences.



073 422 35 55

@ eva.g.596@gmail.com

github.com/egarciamartin

in linkedin.com/in/evagarciamartin/

Work Experience

Data Scientist August 2019 - Present

Ekkono Solutions (Startup), Göteborg, Sweden.

- Prototyping (python) and researching computationally efficient algorithms for Ekkono's enterprise solution, such as gradient boosting, random forest, neural networks, regression trees, and anomaly detection.
- Working with customers from different verticals, mapping use-cases to machine learning problems and data-driven solutions. Business understanding, feature engineering (PCA, signal processing), model selection, deployment, and visualization

Doctoral Student

January 2015 - January 2020

Blekinge Institute of Technology, Karlskrona, Sweden.

- Published and presented research articles (https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=9LJwmLkAAAAJ) in the domain of data stream mining.
- Researched and developed (java, python, C) computationally efficient algorithms for real time training and inference, i.e. decision trees, SVM.

Business Analyst

March 2014 - December 2014

Indra, Madrid, Spain.

Data Analytics on large-scale social datasets using SQL, MongoDB, R, and Python. Presented findings and insights to different customers in an easy-to-understand way through analyses and visualization.

Skills



Education

PhD in Computer Science

2015 - 2020

Blekinge Institute of Technology, Karlskrona, Sweden.

Researched and prototyped computational and memory efficient machine learning algorithms, for data stream mining applications in large-scale datasets.

MSc in Computer Science

2012 - 2013

Blekinge Institute of Technology, Karlskrona, Sweden.

Large-Scale experimentation and statistical analysis on social Twitter data.

BSc in Telecommunications Engineering

2009 - 2013

University Rey Juan Carlos, Madrid, Spain.

Organizing and Volunteering Experience

Tech Advisory Board

May 2021 - Present

Women in Tech Göteborg - Meela

This entails advising the startup on, and through, their product development process ultimately improving the quality of their solution and speeding up their time to market.

Sponsorship Co-Chair

Present

International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Main Organizer and Coordinator

2018 - 2020

Green Data Mining Workshop at European Conference on Machine Learning (ECML)

Volunteer Women in Machine Learning

2017 - 2018

Courses

Languages

Swedish: Conversational

English: Proficient

Spanish: Proficient

Italian: Fluent

Deep Learning Specialization Google Cloud Computer Architecture